hi friends I'm Maru and this is my
YouTube channel and today we are going
to talk about how to choose the best
health insurance so today we are going
to have a look at the best insurance
product in the market and how we are
going to choose it and what are the main
things you have to look out if you are
going to buy the best difference product
so to start with first why to buy an
hintage there are three reasons reasons
which I'm going to list are the
designing factors which will motivate
you to buy your health insurance or in
motivate you to renew the health
insurance because health insurance is
not going to be a one-time purchase
you're going to deliver it so here are
my top three reasons first is the
insurance covered by your company so
many companies or most of the companies
offer a good health insurance cover for
the employees but it's not enough for to
cover all the individuals so in my case
on health insurance covers myself my
wife my kid as well as my parents so it
was good but then the cover was not
enough for all five losses and my
parents being senior citizen so in the
market for senior citizens the health
insurance covers or the cost of the
health insurance is so high so what I
decided is that I can use my company
health insurance coin balance and let me
take a separate cover for three of a
second is your tax service a
Comprehensive Health Insurance in the
market costs around 80 to 20 30 000
bucks if you're on highest tax lab of
thirty percent you can easily save five
to six thousand so if you subtract it's
around 12 000 is what you pay for a
health insurance so instead of giving a
six thousand to the access to the
government be smart and buy your health
insurance and third third is an
ideological fact how to approach a
health insurance product so we have
insurance for our car we have insurance
for our buyer insurance for many things
in our home like a fridge or an EC or
whatever some why not have a health
insurance
which gives you a peace of mind or any
emergency situation so third one is an
ideological one which I think really
motivated me to also buy and health
insurance so if you check any of these
two out of three boxes then you are able
to choose a health insurance there are
three things to find less before we
start a search right these are like
three requisites given before we start
hunting for the products or start
looking at the features the first one is
about choosing the policy should be an
individual or a floral so most of the
policies I have an individual as well as
a floater variants so in my case I chose
a floater for two reasons one being my
kid was not 18 years old individual
policy requires at least 18 years of age
so for a floater only enough floater you
can choose an entire family with us and
then a individual policy truly cause
tired because you have to take it for
every person's and the family means it
will cost higher so floater one was good
to start and it's also budget-free
second one is about the sun um a good
summer shoot for three individuals
should be around 10 or 15 lakhs 10 is
like 100 and a half 15 should be a safe
one I chose 10 lakhs because I found the
research I found out that some insurance
can always be increased at the time of
renewable so and also I have insurance
call with my company so I thought to
start with General lab should be enough
to cover my family of the third reason
is the budget for a good Comprehensive
Health Insurance product in the market
you should be ready to spend around 18
to 20 000 per year anything less than
15K or something will not offer the
features or will have some Riders which
you will come to know only at the time
of any emergencies so have a budget of
18 to 20 for a 10 lakh and for a flow
the having till the Power Research this
thing is to shortlist the products I
chose five providers which are popular
ones in the market first being htfc and
ICICI these are the two biggest private
players in the insurance Market the
third one is Tata I chose datae because
the brand and I had a good experience
with them with their life insurance
policy which I already and fourth one
this is Talent which you know is this is
everyone's favorite and which is Trend
run on the market and the fifth one
being a navi Bupa which is relatively
smaller one but then they offer
excellent features like the other big
players so these are the five different
providers I choose so now let's uh into
the products they offered so every
provider has one or two products in a
segments what I have done I have put in
all the products on my Excel sheets
which I used myself to arrive at the
final decision so I've used extra sheet
where I've put in all the features to
compare uh and shortlist the panel
winner if you heard about stock market
we do fundamental and Technical answers
right so let's do the same thing with
the health insurance as well let's do a
fundamental analysis first let me list
out the features of the fundamental
analysis and technical analysis and then
I will pull up my Excel sheet to compile
the features of the Box the first part
in the fundamental analysis is about
inpatient reading so this is nothing but
your roommate cover so always choose a
provider which or a product which gives
you a good program cover I would say
that shouldn't be any limit in the room
cover provided by the product or it
should be the highest possible category
of room offered while I say this is
because when you choose a higher
category rule it's not only the rent
which you pay extra so also for the
services you base stuff for that
particular category a product which has
the just no limit on the room and the
second is about pre and post
hospitalization uh any surgery or any
plant surgery or any emergency as a free
time barrier to all your reports while
you do all your tests and everything and
there's also a post recovery stage where
where again there are some tests
involved also there are some home health
care needs and other things right so
most of the providers cover this pre and
post as well and as well as the
searching so taking the number of these
I think a minimum of 30 days pre and six
days post is good for a reasonable one
to choose support
third is ayush treatment which is
nothing but other so now uh people have
started using about
ayurveda and other forms of treatment
which also gives a good results right so
most of the products now started
offering covers for those treatments as
well so take a product uh which offers
this benefit now the next one and they
get treatment is nothing but a surgery
Which is less than 20 for hours
insurance and stills you are
hospitalized only if the surgery is more
than 24 hours for anything understand
that it's called declare surgeries and
most of the providers do cover daycare
surgeries I would say an example is
cataract or a dialysis on those kind of
things are like the popular ones and see
if it's covered by your insurance
providers next one is the resale benefit
this is I think I mentioned once the
summit shoes why I chose 10 black as
well right so this recent benefits made
this also I choose to relax for my
sampling shoe so these are benefits in
the future which is offered by a product
where if you fully utilize your
submission and that it gets recent for
that year because they reset your attire
someone should amount which you can
utilize for others since I've insured
others as well it's a total one also we
can place for yourself as well in some
other treatments so this is like you get
a 20 lakh cover you know 10 lakh some
virtual policy this one is your uh
double salary hospitalization which is a
modern home care right so now
postpandabee some most of the treatments
almost the simple ones people do take
care of their homes which means your
providers should cover it right and now
most of the products again offer these
kind of features so Halo policy which
takes care of your home health care as
well that's one being accumulative bonus
this is again a factor which increases
your sum it should so if you have a
clean free your products offer a 50
increase in your summary should subject
to maximum of 100 percentage which is
like 20 lakhs in my case choose a
product which gives you a faster way to
reach W or some issue like most of the
companies have a 50 increase in some
which should as soon as like for First
Financial year and so in two years you
get 20 lakhs in your system issue right
so choose a policy which offers this
week the last one is about non-payables
non-payers are nothing like uh if you
see your bill final bill always required
to pay some amount right and that some
amount a major part of the sum amount
will be about this non-wave it's like
cause this is the sanitizers clouds
these kind of things which uh the
hospital includes uses doing surgeries
or doing your uh stay at hospital right
and these are not covered by the
insurance and when you stay for seven or
eight days in a hospital and these add
up to pretty much Constable amount
please do take product which has this so
these are eight points which you have to
consider for the fundamental things
which should be there in any of your
products before you choose the right
Insurance product for yourself so the
fundamental reason behind taking health
insurance is you don't need to pay all
you don't want to pay any amount from
your pocket in case of emergency right
so these eight points will make sure
that everything is powered and it's also
covered beyond your sandwich and this
comes your technical the first one of
the most technical analysis is about the
network of water planning a surgery you
can do it at any place right so you can
decide on the place you can go to a
different city and also plan to surgery
but if it's an emergency you need you
need a hospital which is nearby which
offers you which is covered by the
insurance provider as well as which
offers cashless uh hospitalization right
so uh have a good product on a provider
who has good Network hospitals in your
area like a place where you live who
often go maybe to your wife's place or
the workplace value so search for I
wouldn't say consider a provider which
has the most Network hospitals because
that's not useful for us but in as I
said take the main areas and see like
the popular hospitals are covered for
you there so this is the first point
second is about the inter-claims ratio
incurred claims ratio is a parameter
where you say where you see how much of
the premiums the insurance provider is
collected from the people and how much
it has even back or settled right so
this is like a premium to subtle
location this number should be uh
between 60 to 100 it's a y range button
is because this says that the company is
paying good it's not keeping the payment
for itself or for the profit it's
clearing some claims also it's receiving
a good amount as premiums right and the
third one is a claim settlement ratio
which is not which is a popular one
right so where it's the issue of the
claims received and they should be uh
mostly about 90 uh for a good uh health
insurance power so these are the three
technical uh parameters and this is just
for giving a view of the company and
health of the company as such yeah now
let's jump into the associated which I
was talking about a lot the Excel sheet
contains the products as well as the
comparison and as well as the parameters
which I've talked about this time so
just I'll pull up Excellency now yeah
sure I'll put in my Excel sheet and you
see other list of products uh which I
will put it on the different columns and
also I'll just put on the features on
every rows so you see here I've chosen
ICICI hell sheet product and then I've
chosen two htlc products optimal secure
and optimal these two and also I have
chosen Navi buffer and Tata a and two
from style in order to list down all the
fundamental features close one to eight
and then technical analysis and also the
other parameters which I have found
useful but which are not deal breakers
for choosing right so as you see here uh
started as the most read uh in the
future wise right because they don't
have for a room limit uh categories they
are probably private rooms which was my
criteria and also don't they don't cover
alternative treatments also they don't
have don't cover the non-payables so
start with is completely gone out of my
shot list it comes uh HDFC hclc again
has a limit on the Roman which does not
fall into my criteria and the other it's
just the product does not cover
alternative treatments so https again
now also take taking into consider the
cost and both of them went outputs and
Tata again has restriction on the wrong
element but other things are good but
they don't have a good recent benefit
which is only once during the policy
period so compared to icci and aliba
Tata offers less so Tata is out and ICC
and now these are the final two ones
which are in my short list right and if
you see any repa is has better features
like it has both are there are no rates
in both products but then if you see
they have unlimited to use reset without
any conditions and they have a good pre
and post hospitalization as well in
neuron technical analysis it has good
Network hospitals ICBC has thousand
final hospitals but then it had the
required it has the required hospitals
in my area so it is uh so for me that
list that that number does not matter
and incurred claims ratio again is good
I mean book as a lesson number which is
again uh not good but then fine if you
say because I said that they in should
be 16 200 right so it's fine and
financial issues again good for about
the companies so the final two short
lists of our email is about icaca and
Nani Bupa and the window is going to be
ics for me icca had a good image than
naidupa for two reasons is a relatively
small company and they have they are a
standalone health insurance provider and
ICICI is a general insurance provider
which produce the insurance of course
all categories and also they have they
have a very large company in fact they
are the number one private insurance in
general insurance companies in our
country so a relatively new company
versus uh an established company right
so this is the fight because we are
taking insurance so that we should not
be worried about uh claims and stuff
right and now when I Googled I heard
some of the claims which are not getting
settled properly uh which had which had
some issues in settlement but I'm not
saying novel is not but it's just about
my personality I am a less risk prone
person I want I want to take a product
which is more secure or lesser scheme so
that's the only reason I chose ICC and I
was ready to play that star premium for
me uh the money always equals to the
product right so uh same features and
even more features is offered grouper
for lesser price that means there is an
issue or that is something which I which
is hidden even though it's not on the
paper and for me it kind of uh did not
feel good so that's why I chose icicn so
it's up to you right so you can I I say
Ravi will pass an excellent product
and put the red markers and see which
offers you but then in for my criteria I
thought Shield is the final winner and
that's going to be a product for my for
this year next year again I will compare
the new products actually existing
products and see if they have improved
their performance and but as of now ICC
system thank you please subscribe to my
channel for any interesting videos like
this in the future and also I have
shared the links where we get this
parameters the insurance regulatory
official website has all the uh product
features the product list and the
wording policy wordings uh so do refer
there for any official information don't
prefer any third party websites I will
share the links in the description as
well as I will also share the links for
the annual reports which contains the
technical parameters which I have
mentioned so both are available in the
insurance circulatory website website to
refer their or the official providers
website don't refer any weapons and also
I will share sexual sheet I'll put the
link in the description please use this
for shortlisting any economy took a lot
of effort to zero on all the products
compare them because I just gave you the
winner maybe in one or two months right
but then it took a lot of time for me to
shortlist the products and shortlist The
Window files so please use this Excel
and choose your best product team uh
stay peacefully see you next video bye
foreign